(
"ai_sub_version": "2.9.1",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 7,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 15,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.1-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true
),
"gemini_cli": (
"timeout": 600,
"overwrite_system_prompt": false
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch"
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"run": 5,
"max": 5,
"delay": 30
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false
)
Attention ご来場のお客様へ
Attention: To all visitors
2次販売グッズ
Second Round Concert Merchandise
ランダムREBOOTコレクション
Random REBOOT Collections
お祝いメッセージボード
Congratulatory Messages from Fans
アニメにハマって
Hooked on anime,
歌いたくなっちゃった
I felt like singing!
推しのシーン見ながら
To be able to sing karaoke
カラオケ歌えるなんて
while watching my favorite scenes...
尊すぎてツライっ！
...is so precious, it hurts!
歌いたいアニメ・ゲームソング見つけよう
Let's find the anime and game songs you want to sing!
ジョイサウンド！
JOYSOUND!
全国のアミューズメント施設でGETしてね♪
Get them at amusement facilities nationwide!
ホロプラス ジャック中 【本日22:00まで】
holoplus JACK in progress [Until 22:00 today]
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon.
【演出の都合上、照明の明滅にご注意ください / 声出し応援OKです】
[Please be aware of flashing lights / Cheering loudly is OK]
【2次販売グッズ / エッセンシャルパック】
[Second-round merchandise / Essentials Pack]
【2次販売グッズ / ライト・Tシャツ・パーカー・缶バッジ・タオル】
[Second-round merchandise / Light, T-shirt, Hoodie, Button Badge, Towel]
【2次販売グッズ / カードケース・キーホルダー・アクリルパネル・タペストリー】
[Second-round merchandise / Card Case, Keychains, Acrylic Panel, Tapestry]
【2次販売グッズ / ランダムREBOOTコレクション】
[Second-round merchandise / Random REBOOT Collections]
Hoshimachi Suisei Live "SuperNova: REBOOT"
開演までしばらくお待ちください
The concert will be starting soon. Please wait a moment.
演出の都合上、照明の明滅にご注意ください / 声出し応援OKです
Please be aware of flashing lights. Cheering loudly is OK.
2次販売グッズ
Second round of concert goods sales
Hoshimachi Suisei Live "SuperNova: REBOOT"
[星街すいせいへの寄せ書きメッセージ]
[Fan Messages for Hoshimachi Suisei]
開演までしばらくお待ちください。
The concert will be starting soon. Please wait a moment.
ご来場のお客様へ：照明の点滅にご注意ください。声出し応援OKです！
Attention: Please be aware of flashing lights. Cheering loudly is OK!
2次販売グッズ：Essentials Pack
Second-Round Merchandise Sales: Essentials Pack
2次販売グッズ：Tシャツ、パーカー、マフラータオル、缶バッジ
Second-Round Merchandise Sales: T-shirt, Hoodie, Towel, Button Badge
2次販売グッズ：キーホルダー、カードケース、アクリルパネル、タペストリー
Second-Round Merchandise Sales: Keychains, Card Case, Acrylic Panel, Tapestry
2次販売グッズ：ランダムREBOOTコレクション
Second-Round Merchandise Sales: Random REBOOT Collections
[星街すいせいへの寄せ書きメッセージ]
[Fan Messages for Hoshimachi Suisei]
本日は、星街すいせいライブ、SuperNova REBOOTにご来場いただき、ありがとうございます。
Thank you for coming to Hoshimachi Suisei Live "SuperNova REBOOT" today.
ありがとうございます。
Thank you very much.
最後までライブを楽しんでいただくために、いくつかご案内させていただきます。
In order for everyone to enjoy the concert until the end, I have a few announcements.
公演中の撮影、録音、録画機材の使用は固くお断りいたします。
The use of photography, recording, and filming equipment during the performance is strictly prohibited.
館内は禁煙となっております。喫煙はご遠慮ください。
The venue is completely non-smoking. Please refrain from smoking.
万が一、具合が悪くなってしまった場合は、無理をせず近くのスタッフへお知らせください。
If you feel unwell, please do not push yourself and let a nearby staff member know.
会場内でのモッシュ、ダイブ、大きく飛び跳ねる、
Acts within the venue such as mosh pits, diving, excessive jumping,
ステージに物を投げ込むなど、他の皆様の迷惑になったり、公演を妨げる行為は一切禁止です。
throwing objects onto the stage, disturbing others, or obstructing the performance are strictly prohibited.
ルールを守って盛り上がってください。
Please follow the rules and have a great time.
みんな今日持ってきてくれてるうちわもね、高く掲げすぎないように気をつけてくださいね。
Everyone, please be careful not to hold up the fans you brought too high today.
ありがとう。後ろの人見えなくなっちゃうからね。
Thank you. We don't want to block the view of the people behind you.
また、本公演は映像配信および写真撮影用のカメラが会場内に入り、客席が映り込む場合がございます。
Also, video recording and photography cameras are in the venue today, so the audience may be captured on screen.
映像や写真はプロモーション等に使用される可能性がございますので、あらかじめご了承ください。
Please be aware in advance that these videos and photos may be used for promotional purposes.
はーい。
Okay!
また、ライブのハッシュタグは、ハッシュタグ「かけめぐる星街さい」です！
Also, the hashtag for this live show is "#KakemeguruHoshimachiSai"!
かわいい！
How cute!
ハッシュタグを使ってたくさん盛り上げてください。
Please use the hashtag to get everyone hyped up!
いっぱい見たいよ、タグ。ありがとね、いっぱい投稿してくれて。
I want to see lots of them! Thank you so much for posting!
それでは、開演までもう少しです！
Well then, it's just a little longer until the show starts!
みんなで一緒に盛り上がりましょう！星街すいせいでした！
Let's all get hyped together! This was Hoshimachi Suisei!
REBOOT
[Title: REBOOT]
星街すいせい
[Title: Hoshimachi Suisei]
革命の、その先へ。
[Title: Beyond the revolution.]
SUPERNOVA REBOOT
[Title: SUPERNOVA REBOOT]
アリーナー！
盛り上がる準備できてますかー？
Are you ready to get hyped up?
さて、すいちゃんはここだよー！
Now, Suichan is right here!
見えてますかー？ここだよー！
Can you see me? I'm here!
お、見つけた見つけた？すいちゃんここだよー！
Oh, did you find me? Suichan is here!
おー、みんなのことよく見える！
Oh, I can see everyone so well!
みんなこっちこっちー！
Everyone, this way, this way!
みんなの持ってるうちわ見せてくださーい！
Show me the concert fans you're holding!
いいねー！みんなの顔よく見えるよー！
Nice! I can see everyone's faces really well!
ぬいぐるみもたくさんありがとうー！
Thank you so much for all the plushies too!
つまんないって 惨憺ね
It's boring, how miserable
奇跡願ってるだけの人生
A life where I'm just wishing for miracles
Watch me 徒手空拳 散々で痛い痛い
Watch me empty-handed, so wretched and painful
トリック無しのマジック
A magic trick with no tricks
Wanna be フリーだって まだ不平だす
Wanting to be free, yet still complaining
...中まで
...to the point of trance.
秒針は音を立てて 夜を急かす
The second hand makes a sound, hurrying the night.
守らなきゃ
I have to protect it.
人生は一瞬にして 溶ける魔法
Life is a magic that melts in an instant.
それならば 駆け抜けて 私だけのストーリー...
If so, I'll run through my own story.
お邪魔な玩具は片付けて
Put away those pesky toys,
ドライビング 私も大変身メイクアップ
driving, I also get a big transformation and make-up.
我儘 まにまに
Selfish as I please,
きらめきに注意注意 そわそわの街で ダンシング
watch out for the sparkle! Dancing in this restless town.
ありがとう！
Thank you!
みなみな！ ご唱和あれ！
Everyone! Sing along!
こんがらがってもしょうがないから 終電で繋いで
It's no use getting tangled up, so connect us with the last train.
今宵にオファーはない ならば夢中になったもん勝ちでしょう
There's no offer tonight, so whoever gets absorbed wins, right?
うー！ 見えてるよー！
Woo! I can see you!
ライダリホ どんな問題も 会話ひとつ
Raidariho! Any problem solved with a single conversation.
複数 正解も間違いも 合図 本当の私リセット
Multiple correct and wrong answers, that's the cue to reset the real me.
あわあわな世界は限界の気配がして...
This bubbly world feels like it's reaching its limit.
うだうだただ安心？いや心配？じゃあ今すぐジャンピンジャンピンナウ
Just lazily feeling relieved? Or worried? Then jump, jump right now!
チクタクバタチクタクバン 偉くだくだくに傷んだハート
Tick-tock batter tick-tock bang, my severely worn-out heart.
ギリギリばっかハプニングだった今 破綻してしまおうか
It was nothing but close-shave happenings, should we break down now?
一発じゃあ全然足りないわ
Just one shot is not nearly enough.
不意に導き出した 君に会った 灰になるまで踊ってよ
Suddenly guided to meet you, dance until we turn to ash!
いくよー！
Here we go!
見えてるよ見えてるよ！...
I can see you, I can see you!
うー！
Woo!
お邪魔な玩具は片付けて
Put away those pesky toys,
ドライビング 私も大変身メイクアップ
driving, I also get a big transformation and make-up.
我儘 まにまに
Selfish as I please,
想いがあふれるのに
Even though my feelings overflow...
ここには僕らしかいられない
there is only us here.
覗いた窓のスプートニクはトバリ
The Sputnik I saw through the window is a veil.
きしむアスファルトに響きを立てていく
Making a sound on the creaking asphalt,
あなたの足音 捉えていたい
I want to capture your footsteps.
みんな、もっともっと声聴かせてください！
Everyone, let me hear your voices even more!
冷え切った太陽に抜かされてずっと
Overtaken by the cold sun, all this time,
縛り付けられているアスファルトの上
I've been tied down on the asphalt.
あぁ 伝ったメッセージが流れ出して
Ah, the conveyed message starts to flow out,
濁った街の底 砕けていく
and crumbles at the bottom of the muddy city.
きっと誰もただ一人で
Surely everyone is just alone,
嘘を吐きながら 耐えながら 吐いてるんだ
spitting lies, enduring, and throwing up.
解りたい 「解ってよ」
I want to understand, "Understand me!"
信じてる 「嘘つき」
"I believe in you," "Liar!"
やんなるくらいの想いが渦巻く
To a sickening extent, my thoughts swirl.
今日も振り回されていく
Today again, I'm being swung around,
脳裏が
and in the back of my mind,
飛び上がる準備をしてる
I'm preparing to jump up.
何もかも反発して
Rebelling against everything,
穿って 滲んでいく
digging deep, and blurring.
冷めきった体温と
With a chilled body temperature,
並んだ無表情に
and the expressions lined up side by side,
臆病になっていた 街の上
I had grown cowardly on top of this city.
阻まる引力と 静まらない超重力
The entangling gravity and the unquietable hypergravity,
名前も意味も何もかもが 決め付けられている
names, meanings, and everything are branded upon us.
なんてどこかで
I make excuses somewhere,
吐いた言い訳が
but those excuses I spat out,
声を奪ったまま
while keeping my voice stolen,
呪いみたいになっていくんだ 今更
are becoming like a curse, at this late hour.
解りたい 「解ってよ」
I want to understand, "Understand me!"
信じてる 「嘘つき」
"I believe in you," "Liar!"
やんなるくらいの想いが渦巻く
To a sickening extent, my thoughts swirl.
今日も振り回されていく
Today again, I'm being swung around,
脳裏が
and in the back of my mind,
飛び上がる準備をしてる
I'm preparing to jump up.
何もかも反発して
Rebelling against everything,
穿って
digging deep,
滲んでいく
and blurring.
もっともっと！
More, more!
手拍子！
Clap your hands!
伝えたい
I want to convey...
愛してる
"I love you,"
大嫌い
"I hate you,"
大好き
"I love you,"
多分 想いの丈の
perhaps even the depth of my feelings...
想いのサイズまで
even to the size of my thoughts...
今日もまた叫んでる
Today again, I'm screaming.
この感情が
Until this emotion...
音の中で
within the sound...
初めて響き合うまで
resonates for the first time,
あなたのその胸で
and within your chest,
響き出すまで
it starts to echo.
愛してる
"I love you,"
大嫌い
"I hate you,"
そうだよ
that's right,
大好き
"I love you!"
すいちゃんはー！
Sui-chan is...!
盛り上がってますねー！
You're really fired up!
ということで、星街すいせいライブ『Supernova ReBoot』、いよいよ始まりましたー！
And so, Hoshimachi Suisei Live: Supernova ReBoot has finally begun!
皆さん、びっくりしたんじゃないですか？
Everyone, weren't you surprised?
冒頭ね。
At the beginning.
ねぇ、一瞬どこにいるかわかんなかったんじゃないかな？
Hey, for a moment, you didn't know where I was, did you?
わかんなかったね？
You didn't, right?
「あれ？出てこない、出てこないぞ？あれ？」って思ったかな？
I wonder if you thought, "Huh? She's not coming out, where is she?"
あの、端っこのね、あの、あそこら辺の人達はね
But those of you at the edges, around that area,
「うおーー！」ってなったかと思いますけれども
I think you all went, "Whoaaa!"
さあ
Now then,
ありがとう！
thank you!
まずは自己紹介からね、いきたいと思いますよ
First, let's start with self-introductions!
彗星の如く現れたスターの原石！バーチャルアイドルの星街すいせいです！
A star's gem that swept in like a comet! I'm virtual idol, Hoshimachi Suisei!
すいちゃんはー？
Sui-chan is...?
（観客）今日も可愛いー！
(Crowd) Cute today too!
いやぁ、元気だね、君たち今日も。
Wow, you guys are so energetic today too.
いやぁ
Geez...
でもさ、まだいけるんじゃない？
But you know, you can do even better, right?
じゃあいくよ？すいちゃんはー？
Alright, here we go! Sui-chan is...?
（観客）今日も可愛いー！
(Crowd) Cute today too!
できるやないかー！
See, you can do it!
さてさて、今回のライブはですね
Well now, for this concert,
去年行いました武道館公演の再演として、
as a rerun of the Budokan concert we did last year,
セトリとかは結構似てるんですけど、
the setlist and everything is quite similar,
2曲目がもうすでに、前回と違いましたね。
but the second song was already different from last time.
ね？
Right?
じゃあ結構なんか変わってたりすんのかな？
So does that mean quite a lot has changed?
とか言って、全然変わってなかったり。
Or maybe I'm saying that, but nothing else has changed.
まあでも、ひとつ言えるのは、
Well, but one thing I can say is,
このKアリーナという会場で、
in this K-Arena venue,
やりたかった演出とか、
the staging we wanted to do...
もう、レーザーバチバチとか、演出がもりもりになってるんで、
the lasers are flashy, and the production is packed,
めちゃめちゃグレードアップしてるんで。
so it has been upgraded a whole lot!
で、私自身もたくさん練習してきましたんで、
And I've also practiced a lot myself,
ダンスとかね、ちょっと頑張ってきたんで。
like the dancing, I worked hard on it.
そういう、去年からパワーアップした姿をお見せできればなと思って、
I wanted to show you how I've powered up since last year,
はい、このライブとなっております。
so yes, that's what this live concert is about.
さて、今回もですね、
Now, this time too,
いつもの通り、バンドさん引き連れております。バンドさーん！
as usual, I have the band with me. Band!
そしてそして、ちょっとリハの動画とかをショートで投稿させてもらってるんですけど、
And also, we've been posting some rehearsal clips as shorts,
気づいた人いるよね？
some of you noticed, right?
今回はストリングスさんがいらっしゃいます！ストリングスさーん！
This time, we have a string section with us! Strings!
もうかっこいいんだから、ストリングスが入るだけでね。
It's already so cool just having strings.
ストリングスって何か知ってる？あの、バイオリン、
Do you know what strings are? Those... violins...
もう今日しか聞けないライブアレンジをね、バンドさんがたくさん、
The band made a lot of live arrangements...
たくさん作ってくださいましたので、
a lot of them that you can only hear today.
もうしょっぱなからビビるほどのね、ストリングス入ったバージョンがかっこよすぎて、
Right from the very start, the version with strings was so cool it startled me,
あげあげになっちゃいましたね。
and I got super hyped up.
めっちゃかっこいい！
It's so cool!
さあ、そしてそして、
And also...
残念ながらここに、来られなかった星詠みたちがいます。
unfortunately, there are Hoshiyomi who couldn't be here today.
ここに来られなかった星詠みたち...
The Hoshiyomi who couldn't make it here...
画面の向こうの君たち！
You guys on the other side of the screen!
「見たかったよー」って言ってる奴、お前、見とるやないか！
To those saying "I wanted to see it!", hey, you're watching it right now!
ちょっとね、なんか、ここら辺になんか、「ここにいるぞ」、あ、なんか見える！
I can see messages around here... "I'm here!" Oh, I can see them!
「見てるよ」、あ、
"I'm watching!" Ah,
「イェーイ！俺はここにいるぞ！」
"Yay! I'm right here!"
お、「行きたかった」、「あ、吊るされてます」、「号泣」。
Oh, "I wanted to go," "Ah, I'm suspended," "Crying hard."
悲しいな。「ニューヨークからこんにちは」あ、ニューヨークからこんにちは！
How sad. "Hello from New York," oh, hello from New York!
え、気になるよ。
Let's see, I'm curious...
海外星詠みの皆さん！
All the overseas Hoshiyomi!
え、海外星詠みではない皆さん！
And everyone who is NOT an overseas Hoshiyomi!
素晴らしい！もうどっちも素晴らしいですね。
Wonderful! Both are wonderful, aren't they?
はい、ということで、配信の方もですね、たくさんファンサしますので、
So yes, I'll be giving lots of fan service to the stream as well,
s:
so I won't let you feel left out!
絶対、最初から最後まで全部見てくださいね。はい、バチコン！
Make sure to watch from beginning to end, okay? Bam!
ではでは、ライブの感想は、ハッシュタグ「#駆け巡る星街」
Now then, for your thoughts on the concert, use the hashtag #駆け巡る星街...
「再」で、たくさんポストしてください。
"再" (Rerun) and please make lots of posts.
ポスト？
Post?
ツイートだよな。
You mean tweet, right?
ツイートだよな。まったく、台本はいつまでもポストって書いてあるんだから。
It's tweet! Honestly, the script always has "post" written on it.
おかしいな。
Strange...
さて、
Now,
YouTube、TikTokでご覧の...
those watching on YouTube or TikTok...
ただで見ているあなた達！
Those of you watching for free!
３曲までよ、ただで見れるのは！
You can only watch up to three songs for free!
えーっ、ありがとう代わりにね、言ってくれて。
Ah, thank you for saying that in my stead.
ありがとう。
Thank you.
さあ、まだまだ一緒に盛り上がりたいみんなは！
Now, everyone who wants to keep hyping it up together...
概要欄から…下なのかな？
...from the description box! Is it below...
上なのかな？下かな？
...or above? Below, I think?
概要欄から配信サイトへレッツゴー！
Go to the streaming site from the description box, let's go!
いいですか皆さん？
Are you ready, everyone?
盛り上がる準備できてますか？次行っちゃっていいですか？
Are you ready to get hyped? Can we go to the next one?
リブートしたSUPERNOVA、全身で浴びてください！
Please bathe in the rebooted SUPERNOVA with your entire body!
無料パートは終了いたしました。ご視聴ありがとうございました！
[On-Screen] The sneak peek part of the show has ended. Thank you for watching.
無料パートは終了いたしました。 ご視聴ありがとうございました！
The sneak peek part of the show has ended. Thank you for watching.